{"problemsArray": [
  {"answer": "(-3, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in 2y + 7 for x into the first equation\n4(2y + 7) + y \u003d -17\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n8y + 28 + y \u003d -17\n9y \u003d -45\ny \u003d -5\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 2y + 7\nx \u003d 2(-5) + 7\nx \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + y \u003d -17\nx \u003d 2y + 7", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in 5x + 1 for y into the first equation\n4(5x + 1) + x \u003d -17\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n20x + 4 + x \u003d -17\n24x \u003d -21\nx \u003d -1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 5x + 1\ny \u003d 5(-1) + 1\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + x \u003d -17\ny \u003d 5x + 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in x - 1 for y into the first equation\n3(x - 1) + 3x \u003d -27\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n3x - 3 + 3x \u003d -27\n6x \u003d -24\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d x - 1\ny \u003d (-4) - 1\ny \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + 3x \u003d -27\ny \u003d x - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x + 13 for y into the first equation\n4(3x + 13) + 3x \u003d -8\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n12x + 52 + 3x \u003d -8\n16x \u003d -60\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x + 13\ny \u003d 3(-4) + 13\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + 3x \u003d -8\ny \u003d 3x + 13", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x - 5 for y into the first equation\n3(-3x - 5) + 4x \u003d -10\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-9x - 15 + 4x \u003d -10\n-6x \u003d 5\nx \u003d -1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x - 5\ny \u003d -3(-1) - 5\ny \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + 4x \u003d -10\ny \u003d -3x - 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in 2y + 1 for x into the first equation\n4(2y + 1) + y \u003d -23\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n8y + 4 + y \u003d -23\n9y \u003d -27\ny \u003d -3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 2y + 1\nx \u003d 2(-3) + 1\nx \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + y \u003d -23\nx \u003d 2y + 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in -2x - 1 for y into the first equation\n(-2x - 1) + x \u003d -2\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-2x - 1 + x \u003d -2\n-x \u003d -1\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -2x - 1\ny \u003d -2(1) - 1\ny \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d -2\ny \u003d -2x - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-2, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in -4y - 22 for x into the first equation\n4(-4y - 22) + 3y \u003d -23\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-16y - 88 + 3y \u003d -23\n-13y \u003d 65\ny \u003d -5\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -4y - 22\nx \u003d -4(-5) - 22\nx \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + 3y \u003d -23\nx \u003d -4y - 22", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x - 5 for y into the first equation\n4(-3x - 5) - 2x \u003d -6\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-12x - 20 - 2x \u003d -6\n-8x \u003d 14\nx \u003d -1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x - 5\ny \u003d -3(-1) - 5\ny \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y - 2x \u003d -6\ny \u003d -3x - 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x - 5 for y into the first equation\n(3x - 5) + 3x \u003d 1\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n3x - 5 + 3x \u003d 1\n4x \u003d 6\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x - 5\ny \u003d 3(1) - 5\ny \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 3x \u003d 1\ny \u003d 3x - 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in 5x - 10 for y into the first equation\n4(5x - 10) + 4x \u003d 32\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n20x - 40 + 4x \u003d 32\n24x \u003d 72\nx \u003d 3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 5x - 10\ny \u003d 5(3) - 10\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + 4x \u003d 32\ny \u003d 5x - 10", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in -y + 0 for x into the first equation\n2(-y + 0) + 2y \u003d 0\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-2y + 0 + 2y \u003d 0\n \u003d 0\ny \u003d -1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -y + 0\nx \u003d -(-1) + 0\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2x + 2y \u003d 0\nx \u003d -y + 0", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x + 8 for y into the first equation\n(3x + 8) - 2x \u003d 5\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n3x + 8 - 2x \u003d 5\n4x \u003d -3\nx \u003d -3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x + 8\ny \u003d 3(-3) + 8\ny \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny - 2x \u003d 5\ny \u003d 3x + 8", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in -x - 2 for y into the first equation\n(-x - 2) + 4x \u003d 1\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-1x - 2 + 4x \u003d 1\n \u003d 3\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x - 2\ny \u003d -(1) - 2\ny \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 4x \u003d 1\ny \u003d -x - 2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in -4x - 16 for y into the first equation\n(-4x - 16) + 5x \u003d -19\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-4x - 16 + 5x \u003d -19\n-3x \u003d -3\nx \u003d -3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -4x - 16\ny \u003d -4(-3) - 16\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 5x \u003d -19\ny \u003d -4x - 16", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in 2y - 5 for x into the first equation\n3(2y - 5) + 4y \u003d 15\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n6y - 15 + 4y \u003d 15\n10y \u003d 30\ny \u003d 3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 2y - 5\nx \u003d 2(3) - 5\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x + 4y \u003d 15\nx \u003d 2y - 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in 5x + 15 for y into the first equation\n3(5x + 15) + 4x \u003d -31\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n15x + 45 + 4x \u003d -31\n18x \u003d -76\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 5x + 15\ny \u003d 5(-4) + 15\ny \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + 4x \u003d -31\ny \u003d 5x + 15", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x - 1 for y into the first equation\n3(-3x - 1) - 2x \u003d -14\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-9x - 3 - 2x \u003d -14\n-6x \u003d -11\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x - 1\ny \u003d -3(1) - 1\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y - 2x \u003d -14\ny \u003d -3x - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in -4y - 11 for x into the first equation\n(-4y - 11) + 2y \u003d -7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-4y - 11 + 2y \u003d -7\n-2y \u003d 4\ny \u003d -2\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -4y - 11\nx \u003d -4(-2) - 11\nx \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + 2y \u003d -7\nx \u003d -4y - 11", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in -4x - 1 for y into the first equation\n3(-4x - 1) + 3x \u003d 6\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-12x - 3 + 3x \u003d 6\n-9x \u003d 9\nx \u003d -1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -4x - 1\ny \u003d -4(-1) - 1\ny \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + 3x \u003d 6\ny \u003d -4x - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x - 8 for y into the first equation\n2(-3x - 8) - x \u003d 12\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-6x - 16 - x \u003d 12\n-4x \u003d 28\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x - 8\ny \u003d -3(-4) - 8\ny \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y - x \u003d 12\ny \u003d -3x - 8", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x + 18 for y into the first equation\n(-3x + 18) + 4x \u003d 23\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-3x + 18 + 4x \u003d 23\n-2x \u003d 5\nx \u003d 5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x + 18\ny \u003d -3(5) + 18\ny \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 4x \u003d 23\ny \u003d -3x + 18", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in 0y + 1 for x into the first equation\n4(0y + 1) - y \u003d 6\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n0y + 4 - y \u003d 6\n-y \u003d 2\ny \u003d -2\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 0y + 1\nx \u003d 0(-2) + 1\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x - y \u003d 6\nx \u003d 0y + 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in 4y + 18 for x into the first equation\n3(4y + 18) - y \u003d 10\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n12y + 54 - y \u003d 10\n1y \u003d -44\ny \u003d -4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 4y + 18\nx \u003d 4(-4) + 18\nx \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x - y \u003d 10\nx \u003d 4y + 18", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in -x + 6 for y into the first equation\n3(-x + 6) + 2x \u003d 13\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-3x + 18 + 2x \u003d 13\n \u003d -5\nx \u003d 5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x + 6\ny \u003d -(5) + 6\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + 2x \u003d 13\ny \u003d -x + 6", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in -2x + 11 for y into the first equation\n3(-2x + 11) + 5x \u003d 29\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-6x + 33 + 5x \u003d 29\n-3x \u003d -4\nx \u003d 4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -2x + 11\ny \u003d -2(4) + 11\ny \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + 5x \u003d 29\ny \u003d -2x + 11", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in 2x - 3 for y into the first equation\n(2x - 3) + 2x \u003d 5\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n2x - 3 + 2x \u003d 5\n3x \u003d 8\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 2x - 3\ny \u003d 2(2) - 3\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 2x \u003d 5\ny \u003d 2x - 3", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in x - 2 for y into the first equation\n3(x - 2) + x \u003d -18\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n3x - 6 + x \u003d -18\n6x \u003d -12\nx \u003d -3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d x - 2\ny \u003d (-3) - 2\ny \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + x \u003d -18\ny \u003d x - 2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(6, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in -4x + 29 for y into the first equation\n4(-4x + 29) - 2x \u003d 8\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-16x + 116 - 2x \u003d 8\n-12x \u003d -108\nx \u003d 6\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -4x + 29\ny \u003d -4(6) + 29\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y - 2x \u003d 8\ny \u003d -4x + 29", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in -3y + 13 for x into the first equation\n2(-3y + 13) + 2y \u003d 10\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-6y + 26 + 2y \u003d 10\n-4y \u003d -16\ny \u003d 4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -3y + 13\nx \u003d -3(4) + 13\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2x + 2y \u003d 10\nx \u003d -3y + 13", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in 2x + 2 for y into the first equation\n(2x + 2) + x \u003d -7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n2x + 2 + x \u003d -7\n3x \u003d -9\nx \u003d -3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 2x + 2\ny \u003d 2(-3) + 2\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d -7\ny \u003d 2x + 2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in -3y + 0 for x into the first equation\n(-3y + 0) + y \u003d 2\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-3y + 0 + y \u003d 2\n-2y \u003d 2\ny \u003d -1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -3y + 0\nx \u003d -3(-1) + 0\nx \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + y \u003d 2\nx \u003d -3y + 0", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in -y - 4 for x into the first equation\n3(-y - 4) + 2y \u003d -11\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-3y - 12 + 2y \u003d -11\n-y \u003d 1\ny \u003d -1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -y - 4\nx \u003d -(-1) - 4\nx \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x + 2y \u003d -11\nx \u003d -y - 4", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in 4y + 16 for x into the first equation\n(4y + 16) + 3y \u003d -19\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n4y + 16 + 3y \u003d -19\n7y \u003d -35\ny \u003d -5\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 4y + 16\nx \u003d 4(-5) + 16\nx \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + 3y \u003d -19\nx \u003d 4y + 16", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in 2x + 5 for y into the first equation\n3(2x + 5) + x \u003d -13\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n6x + 15 + x \u003d -13\n9x \u003d -28\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 2x + 5\ny \u003d 2(-4) + 5\ny \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + x \u003d -13\ny \u003d 2x + 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y + 6 for x into the first equation\n2(-2y + 6) + 3y \u003d 11\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-4y + 12 + 3y \u003d 11\n-y \u003d -1\ny \u003d 1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y + 6\nx \u003d -2(1) + 6\nx \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2x + 3y \u003d 11\nx \u003d -2y + 6", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x - 4 for y into the first equation\n(3x - 4) + 2x \u003d 1\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n3x - 4 + 2x \u003d 1\n4x \u003d 5\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x - 4\ny \u003d 3(1) - 4\ny \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 2x \u003d 1\ny \u003d 3x - 4", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x - 14 for y into the first equation\n4(3x - 14) + 3x \u003d 4\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n12x - 56 + 3x \u003d 4\n16x \u003d 60\nx \u003d 4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x - 14\ny \u003d 3(4) - 14\ny \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + 3x \u003d 4\ny \u003d 3x - 14", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in -y + 0 for x into the first equation\n3(-y + 0) - y \u003d -12\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-3y + 0 - y \u003d -12\n-4y \u003d -12\ny \u003d 3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -y + 0\nx \u003d -(3) + 0\nx \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x - y \u003d -12\nx \u003d -y + 0", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in -x + 0 for y into the first equation\n(-x + 0) + 4x \u003d 3\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-1x + 0 + 4x \u003d 3\n \u003d 3\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x + 0\ny \u003d -(1) + 0\ny \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 4x \u003d 3\ny \u003d -x + 0", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x + 3 for y into the first equation\n4(-3x + 3) - 2x \u003d -16\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-12x + 12 - 2x \u003d -16\n-8x \u003d -28\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x + 3\ny \u003d -3(2) + 3\ny \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y - 2x \u003d -16\ny \u003d -3x + 3", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in -x + 7 for y into the first equation\n(-x + 7) - 2x \u003d -2\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-1x + 7 - 2x \u003d -2\n \u003d -9\nx \u003d 3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x + 7\ny \u003d -(3) + 7\ny \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny - 2x \u003d -2\ny \u003d -x + 7", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in x - 9 for y into the first equation\n2(x - 9) + 5x \u003d 17\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n2x - 18 + 5x \u003d 17\n4x \u003d 35\nx \u003d 5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d x - 9\ny \u003d (5) - 9\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + 5x \u003d 17\ny \u003d x - 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in y - 8 for x into the first equation\n2(y - 8) + 3y \u003d 4\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n2y - 16 + 3y \u003d 4\n5y \u003d 20\ny \u003d 4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d y - 8\nx \u003d (4) - 8\nx \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2x + 3y \u003d 4\nx \u003d y - 8", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in -3y + 15 for x into the first equation\n3(-3y + 15) + y \u003d 13\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-9y + 45 + y \u003d 13\n-8y \u003d -32\ny \u003d 4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -3y + 15\nx \u003d -3(4) + 15\nx \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x + y \u003d 13\nx \u003d -3y + 15", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in -4y - 1 for x into the first equation\n(-4y - 1) - y \u003d 4\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-4y - 1 - y \u003d 4\n-5y \u003d 5\ny \u003d -1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -4y - 1\nx \u003d -4(-1) - 1\nx \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx - y \u003d 4\nx \u003d -4y - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in 4x + 13 for y into the first equation\n(4x + 13) + x \u003d -7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n4x + 13 + x \u003d -7\n5x \u003d -20\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 4x + 13\ny \u003d 4(-4) + 13\ny \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d -7\ny \u003d 4x + 13", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in 5y - 17 for x into the first equation\n4(5y - 17) - 2y \u003d 4\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n20y - 68 - 2y \u003d 4\n18y \u003d 72\ny \u003d 4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 5y - 17\nx \u003d 5(4) - 17\nx \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x - 2y \u003d 4\nx \u003d 5y - 17", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in -3y + 8 for x into the first equation\n2(-3y + 8) + y \u003d 1\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-6y + 16 + y \u003d 1\n-5y \u003d -15\ny \u003d 3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -3y + 8\nx \u003d -3(3) + 8\nx \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2x + y \u003d 1\nx \u003d -3y + 8", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in 4y + 9 for x into the first equation\n3(4y + 9) + 4y \u003d 11\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n12y + 27 + 4y \u003d 11\n16y \u003d -16\ny \u003d -1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 4y + 9\nx \u003d 4(-1) + 9\nx \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x + 4y \u003d 11\nx \u003d 4y + 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x + 16 for y into the first equation\n2(-3x + 16) + 2x \u003d 12\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-6x + 32 + 2x \u003d 12\n-4x \u003d -20\nx \u003d 5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x + 16\ny \u003d -3(5) + 16\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + 2x \u003d 12\ny \u003d -3x + 16", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y - 5 for x into the first equation\n4(-2y - 5) + 3y \u003d -5\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-8y - 20 + 3y \u003d -5\n-5y \u003d 15\ny \u003d -3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y - 5\nx \u003d -2(-3) - 5\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + 3y \u003d -5\nx \u003d -2y - 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in 2x + 13 for y into the first equation\n(2x + 13) + x \u003d 1\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n2x + 13 + x \u003d 1\n3x \u003d -12\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 2x + 13\ny \u003d 2(-4) + 13\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d 1\ny \u003d 2x + 13", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(6, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in 0x + 5 for y into the first equation\n4(0x + 5) - x \u003d 14\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n0x + 20 - x \u003d 14\n4x \u003d -6\nx \u003d 6\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 0x + 5\ny \u003d 0(6) + 5\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y - x \u003d 14\ny \u003d 0x + 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in 5x - 27 for y into the first equation\n2(5x - 27) + 3x \u003d 11\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n10x - 54 + 3x \u003d 11\n12x \u003d 65\nx \u003d 5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 5x - 27\ny \u003d 5(5) - 27\ny \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + 3x \u003d 11\ny \u003d 5x - 27", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-2, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in 4x + 13 for y into the first equation\n4(4x + 13) - x \u003d 22\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n16x + 52 - x \u003d 22\n20x \u003d -30\nx \u003d -2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 4x + 13\ny \u003d 4(-2) + 13\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y - x \u003d 22\ny \u003d 4x + 13", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in 4y + 17 for x into the first equation\n(4y + 17) + y \u003d 2\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n4y + 17 + y \u003d 2\n5y \u003d -15\ny \u003d -3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 4y + 17\nx \u003d 4(-3) + 17\nx \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + y \u003d 2\nx \u003d 4y + 17", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in 5y + 19 for x into the first equation\n(5y + 19) - 2y \u003d 7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n5y + 19 - 2y \u003d 7\n3y \u003d -12\ny \u003d -4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 5y + 19\nx \u003d 5(-4) + 19\nx \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx - 2y \u003d 7\nx \u003d 5y + 19", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in -x + 7 for y into the first equation\n2(-x + 7) + 2x \u003d 14\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-2x + 14 + 2x \u003d 14\n \u003d 0\nx \u003d 4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x + 7\ny \u003d -(4) + 7\ny \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + 2x \u003d 14\ny \u003d -x + 7", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x - 19 for y into the first equation\n(-3x - 19) + x \u003d -9\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-3x - 19 + x \u003d -9\n-2x \u003d 10\nx \u003d -5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x - 19\ny \u003d -3(-5) - 19\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d -9\ny \u003d -3x - 19", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in -x + 1 for y into the first equation\n(-x + 1) + 3x \u003d -5\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-1x + 1 + 3x \u003d -5\n \u003d -6\nx \u003d -3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x + 1\ny \u003d -(-3) + 1\ny \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 3x \u003d -5\ny \u003d -x + 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in -4y - 12 for x into the first equation\n(-4y - 12) + 3y \u003d -10\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-4y - 12 + 3y \u003d -10\n-y \u003d 2\ny \u003d -2\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -4y - 12\nx \u003d -4(-2) - 12\nx \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + 3y \u003d -10\nx \u003d -4y - 12", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in -5x - 22 for y into the first equation\n2(-5x - 22) + 4x \u003d -20\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-10x - 44 + 4x \u003d -20\n-8x \u003d 24\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -5x - 22\ny \u003d -5(-4) - 22\ny \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + 4x \u003d -20\ny \u003d -5x - 22", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x + 2 for y into the first equation\n(3x + 2) + x \u003d 6\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n3x + 2 + x \u003d 6\n4x \u003d 4\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x + 2\ny \u003d 3(1) + 2\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d 6\ny \u003d 3x + 2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in 2y + 9 for x into the first equation\n2(2y + 9) + 3y \u003d -10\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n4y + 18 + 3y \u003d -10\n7y \u003d -28\ny \u003d -4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 2y + 9\nx \u003d 2(-4) + 9\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2x + 3y \u003d -10\nx \u003d 2y + 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y - 3 for x into the first equation\n(-2y - 3) + 4y \u003d -11\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-2y - 3 + 4y \u003d -11\n2y \u003d -8\ny \u003d -4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y - 3\nx \u003d -2(-4) - 3\nx \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + 4y \u003d -11\nx \u003d -2y - 3", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-2, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in 4x + 5 for y into the first equation\n4(4x + 5) - x \u003d -10\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n16x + 20 - x \u003d -10\n20x \u003d -30\nx \u003d -2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 4x + 5\ny \u003d 4(-2) + 5\ny \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y - x \u003d -10\ny \u003d 4x + 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in 4x + 14 for y into the first equation\n(4x + 14) + x \u003d -6\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n4x + 14 + x \u003d -6\n5x \u003d -20\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 4x + 14\ny \u003d 4(-4) + 14\ny \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d -6\ny \u003d 4x + 14", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x + 13 for y into the first equation\n4(3x + 13) + 4x \u003d -12\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n12x + 52 + 4x \u003d -12\n16x \u003d -64\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x + 13\ny \u003d 3(-4) + 13\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + 4x \u003d -12\ny \u003d 3x + 13", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in -4x - 15 for y into the first equation\n(-4x - 15) + 3x \u003d -11\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-4x - 15 + 3x \u003d -11\n-3x \u003d 4\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -4x - 15\ny \u003d -4(-4) - 15\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 3x \u003d -11\ny \u003d -4x - 15", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in x - 8 for y into the first equation\n(x - 8) + 5x \u003d 22\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n1x - 8 + 5x \u003d 22\n2x \u003d 30\nx \u003d 5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d x - 8\ny \u003d (5) - 8\ny \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 5x \u003d 22\ny \u003d x - 8", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, 2)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x - 1 for y into the first equation\n4(3x - 1) - x \u003d 7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n12x - 4 - x \u003d 7\n16x \u003d 11\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x - 1\ny \u003d 3(1) - 1\ny \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y - x \u003d 7\ny \u003d 3x - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in -4x - 24 for y into the first equation\n4(-4x - 24) + x \u003d -21\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-16x - 96 + x \u003d -21\n-12x \u003d 75\nx \u003d -5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -4x - 24\ny \u003d -4(-5) - 24\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + x \u003d -21\ny \u003d -4x - 24", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in 5y + 26 for x into the first equation\n(5y + 26) + y \u003d -4\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n5y + 26 + y \u003d -4\n6y \u003d -30\ny \u003d -5\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 5y + 26\nx \u003d 5(-5) + 26\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + y \u003d -4\nx \u003d 5y + 26", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in -2x + 5 for y into the first equation\n(-2x + 5) + 3x \u003d 7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-2x + 5 + 3x \u003d 7\n-x \u003d 2\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -2x + 5\ny \u003d -2(2) + 5\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 3x \u003d 7\ny \u003d -2x + 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in 5x - 29 for y into the first equation\n(5x - 29) - 2x \u003d -14\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n5x - 29 - 2x \u003d -14\n6x \u003d 15\nx \u003d 5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 5x - 29\ny \u003d 5(5) - 29\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny - 2x \u003d -14\ny \u003d 5x - 29", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in y - 8 for x into the first equation\n(y - 8) + y \u003d 0\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n1y - 8 + y \u003d 0\n2y \u003d 8\ny \u003d 4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d y - 8\nx \u003d (4) - 8\nx \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + y \u003d 0\nx \u003d y - 8", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 2)", "explanation": "Plug in -2x + 10 for y into the first equation\n2(-2x + 10) + x \u003d 8\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-4x + 20 + x \u003d 8\n-2x \u003d -12\nx \u003d 4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -2x + 10\ny \u003d -2(4) + 10\ny \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + x \u003d 8\ny \u003d -2x + 10", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y - 1 for x into the first equation\n(-2y - 1) + y \u003d 0\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-2y - 1 + y \u003d 0\n-y \u003d 1\ny \u003d -1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y - 1\nx \u003d -2(-1) - 1\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + y \u003d 0\nx \u003d -2y - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in -x - 2 for y into the first equation\n(-x - 2) - x \u003d -6\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-1x - 2 - x \u003d -6\n \u003d -4\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x - 2\ny \u003d -(2) - 2\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny - x \u003d -6\ny \u003d -x - 2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, 2)", "explanation": "Plug in -3y + 1 for x into the first equation\n4(-3y + 1) + 4y \u003d -12\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-12y + 4 + 4y \u003d -12\n-8y \u003d -16\ny \u003d 2\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -3y + 1\nx \u003d -3(2) + 1\nx \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + 4y \u003d -12\nx \u003d -3y + 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in -x + 7 for y into the first equation\n2(-x + 7) - 2x \u003d 6\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-2x + 14 - 2x \u003d 6\n \u003d -8\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x + 7\ny \u003d -(2) + 7\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y - 2x \u003d 6\ny \u003d -x + 7", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in -4x - 11 for y into the first equation\n(-4x - 11) + 3x \u003d -7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-4x - 11 + 3x \u003d -7\n-3x \u003d 4\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -4x - 11\ny \u003d -4(-4) - 11\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 3x \u003d -7\ny \u003d -4x - 11", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y - 5 for x into the first equation\n3(-2y - 5) + y \u003d 0\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-6y - 15 + y \u003d 0\n-5y \u003d 15\ny \u003d -3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y - 5\nx \u003d -2(-3) - 5\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x + y \u003d 0\nx \u003d -2y - 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x + 14 for y into the first equation\n2(3x + 14) + 2x \u003d 4\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n6x + 28 + 2x \u003d 4\n8x \u003d -24\nx \u003d -3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x + 14\ny \u003d 3(-3) + 14\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + 2x \u003d 4\ny \u003d 3x + 14", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in 5x - 9 for y into the first equation\n3(5x - 9) + 2x \u003d -10\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n15x - 27 + 2x \u003d -10\n18x \u003d 17\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 5x - 9\ny \u003d 5(1) - 9\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + 2x \u003d -10\ny \u003d 5x - 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in 4x - 17 for y into the first equation\n(4x - 17) + x \u003d 3\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n4x - 17 + x \u003d 3\n5x \u003d 20\nx \u003d 4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 4x - 17\ny \u003d 4(4) - 17\ny \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d 3\ny \u003d 4x - 17", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-2, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x + 7 for y into the first equation\n3(3x + 7) + 3x \u003d -3\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n9x + 21 + 3x \u003d -3\n12x \u003d -24\nx \u003d -2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x + 7\ny \u003d 3(-2) + 7\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + 3x \u003d -3\ny \u003d 3x + 7", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in -y + 9 for x into the first equation\n3(-y + 9) + 3y \u003d 27\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-3y + 27 + 3y \u003d 27\n \u003d 0\ny \u003d 5\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -y + 9\nx \u003d -(5) + 9\nx \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x + 3y \u003d 27\nx \u003d -y + 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x + 2 for y into the first equation\n(-3x + 2) + x \u003d 0\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-3x + 2 + x \u003d 0\n-2x \u003d -2\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x + 2\ny \u003d -3(1) + 2\ny \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d 0\ny \u003d -3x + 2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y - 7 for x into the first equation\n4(-2y - 7) + y \u003d -14\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-8y - 28 + y \u003d -14\n-7y \u003d 14\ny \u003d -2\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y - 7\nx \u003d -2(-2) - 7\nx \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + y \u003d -14\nx \u003d -2y - 7", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in -y + 8 for x into the first equation\n4(-y + 8) + 5y \u003d 35\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-4y + 32 + 5y \u003d 35\ny \u003d 3\ny \u003d 3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -y + 8\nx \u003d -(3) + 8\nx \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + 5y \u003d 35\nx \u003d -y + 8", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, 2)", "explanation": "Plug in -x + 1 for y into the first equation\n3(-x + 1) + 4x \u003d 2\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-3x + 3 + 4x \u003d 2\n \u003d -1\nx \u003d -1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x + 1\ny \u003d -(-1) + 1\ny \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + 4x \u003d 2\ny \u003d -x + 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y + 8 for x into the first equation\n3(-2y + 8) + y \u003d 9\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-6y + 24 + y \u003d 9\n-5y \u003d -15\ny \u003d 3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y + 8\nx \u003d -2(3) + 8\nx \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x + y \u003d 9\nx \u003d -2y + 8", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x + 8 for y into the first equation\n4(-3x + 8) + 2x \u003d 2\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-12x + 32 + 2x \u003d 2\n-8x \u003d -30\nx \u003d 3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x + 8\ny \u003d -3(3) + 8\ny \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + 2x \u003d 2\ny \u003d -3x + 8", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in 5y - 2 for x into the first equation\n(5y - 2) - 2y \u003d 1\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n5y - 2 - 2y \u003d 1\n3y \u003d 3\ny \u003d 1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 5y - 2\nx \u003d 5(1) - 2\nx \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx - 2y \u003d 1\nx \u003d 5y - 2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, 2)", "explanation": "Plug in 5x - 3 for y into the first equation\n2(5x - 3) + 2x \u003d 6\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n10x - 6 + 2x \u003d 6\n12x \u003d 12\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 5x - 3\ny \u003d 5(1) - 3\ny \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + 2x \u003d 6\ny \u003d 5x - 3", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in 3y + 4 for x into the first equation\n4(3y + 4) + y \u003d 3\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n12y + 16 + y \u003d 3\n13y \u003d -13\ny \u003d -1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 3y + 4\nx \u003d 3(-1) + 4\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + y \u003d 3\nx \u003d 3y + 4", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, 2)", "explanation": "Plug in 2y - 9 for x into the first equation\n(2y - 9) + y \u003d -3\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n2y - 9 + y \u003d -3\n3y \u003d 6\ny \u003d 2\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 2y - 9\nx \u003d 2(2) - 9\nx \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + y \u003d -3\nx \u003d 2y - 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, 2)", "explanation": "Plug in 3y - 5 for x into the first equation\n3(3y - 5) - 2y \u003d -1\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n9y - 15 - 2y \u003d -1\n7y \u003d 14\ny \u003d 2\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 3y - 5\nx \u003d 3(2) - 5\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x - 2y \u003d -1\nx \u003d 3y - 5", "type": "text"}
]}